# RIONA MCCUMSKAY

# **Junior Software Developer**

r.mccumskay@gmail.com

0780 5761 756

Manchester

github.com/Rionagrace

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/riona-mccumskay/

# Personal profile

Northcoders software development bootcamp graduate, with past experience as a freelance assistant producer with 7 years experience producing programming for television. Making the career change to software development as it is an area I've always been interested in since I coded my first maze game in high school. I'm passionate about the environment and making the world a better place through code.

## Technical skills

Languages: JavaScript, using Node is and browsers as environment

Testing: TDD (Test Driven Development), Jest, Supertest

Back-end: SQL, PSQL, seeding, migrations

HTML, CSS, React, React-Native, Expo, MapBox, Lighthouse and other accessibility tools Front-end:

Cloud: Cloudflare, Netlify, AWS

Other: Paired programming, technical communication, SDL, Agile and SCRUM methodologies

# **Projects**

### hisTOURy

**Technologies:** React Native, MapBox, Expo, Supabase (PostGIS extension)

HisTOURy is an app where users can build their own guided tour, exploring historical locations in their local area. This was a group project built using agile methodologies, in which I contributed the original idea plus the map and planner pages.

Link to demo video — https://github.com/Rionagrace/NC-final-project

#### **NC News**

**Technologies:** React, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, JavaScript (TDD)

Full stack project replicating the functionality of a news website, including viewing/sorting articles, log in authentication plus posting articles and comments.

https://github.com/Rionagrace/NC-News-Frontend/

#### **Pokemon Finder**

Technologies: React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PokeAPI

Pokemon Finder is a webpage that allows users to search for their favourite pokemon, as well as view all Pokemon from each generation within the universe.

https://github.com/Rionagrace/pokemon-finder

# **Experience**

#### TRAINEE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### Northcoders Bootcamp | September 2024 - November 2024

- Completed an intensive full-time software development course focused on JavaScript, front-end, and back-end development.
- Collaborated using Agile methodologies, emphasising paired programming and technical communication.
- Developed strong TDD practices for writing robust and maintainable code.

#### FREELANCE ASSISTANT PRODUCER

#### Various Projects | April 2022 - August 2024

- Produced and managed programming for high-profile shows like The Apprentice and Casualty 24/7.
- Pitched innovative ideas, planned shoots, and solved on-set challenges creatively.
- Communicated effectively with diverse teams, enhancing production workflows.

#### FREELANCE PRODUCER

## All Star Shore | January 2023

- Leading a team of 10 to produce solo content for a reality television show.
- Producing solo content, conceptualising shoots and producing on shoot days.

#### FREELANCE RESEARCHER

## Various Projects | July 2018 - April 2022

- Supported editorial teams in planning and executing content for shows like The Circle and Chateau DIY.
- Developed organisational and problem-solving skills in high-pressure production environments.

## **Education**

#### **BATV AND RADIO PRODUCTION**

University of Salford - 1st class degree.

Degree focussing on the practical and technical skills in television/radio production. Specialising in developing and pitching ideas, writing treatments and creative writing.

# **Hobbies and interests**

- Regular at Manc.js (javascript coding group) and Women In Tech
- I love going on hikes in the Peak District and finding the best wild swimming spots (soft spot for a waterfall)
- Collecting vinyl of movie soundtracks (80s films are the best)